<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/</link><description>Recent content on AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr Dwijavanthi Kumar</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/dwijavanthi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/dwijavanthi/</guid><description>She is an attending Family Medicine Physician at One Community Health, OB Physician Lead, UC-Davis Volunteer Clinical Faculty, and Program Director of KT-AFPI Primary Care Leadership Fellowship.
Education Bachelors of Science in Biomedical Engineering – University of Iowa, 2008 Dual MD and MPH Program – University of Iowa, Carver College of Medicine, 2015 Family Medicine Residency – Santa Rosa Family Medicine -2018 Dwijavanthi was born in Bangalore, India and immigrated to the US at the age of 7.</description></item><item><title>Dr H Sudarshan</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/h-sudarshan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/h-sudarshan/</guid><description>Dr. Hanumappa Sudarshan is an Indian social worker and tribal rights activist. He is well known for his contributions to the upliftment of the forest dwelling tribes (mainly Soligas) in the Chamarajanagar district of Karnataka. He is also a recipient of the Right Livelihood Award and the Padma Shri. Sudarshan was born in Yemalur on the outskirts of Bangalore. He graduated from Bangalore Medical College and became a medical doctor in the year 1973.</description></item><item><title>Dr BC Rao</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/badakere-rao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/badakere-rao/</guid><description>One of the early DNBs in family medicine, teacher and trainer in family medicine over 40 years who built up the Family physicians association in Bangalore from a handful of members to over a thousand members at present. He ran numerous courses for Family Physicians over the years. He has been an examiner for both DNB and FCGP in the past. He was honored to give the keynote address on the inaugural day of the national conference of family medicine FMPC 2018.</description></item><item><title>Dr Eric Wilson</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/eric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/eric/</guid><description>He is an attending Family Medicine Physician, One Community Health, UC Davis Volunteer Clinical Faculty, and KT-AFPI Primary Care Leadership Fellowship Core Faculty.
Education BS in Economics, Math, and French – Iowa State University, 2008 MA in Economics – Duke University, 2010 MD – University of Iowa, 2016 Family Medicine Residency – Santa Rosa Family Medicine – 2019 Primary Care in Psychiatry Fellowship – UC Davis, 2020 Eric was born and raised in Dubuque, Iowa.</description></item><item><title>Venkat Chekuri</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/venkat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/venkat/</guid><description>Prior to Karuna Trust, Venkat joined Vivekananda Kendra, Kanyakumari as a full time worker. After initial training, he went to Arunachal Pradesh to be part of the Integrated Tribal Development programme. He worked as the Secretary of the project at the time of leaving the organization in the year 1998. He then joined Dr. Sudarshan in Tribal and Rural Development organisations namely Vivekananda Girijana Kalyana Kendra (VGKK) and Karuna Trust. Venkat has worked in different capacities in both organizations and became the Trustee of Karuna Trust in the year 2002.</description></item><item><title>Dr Shailendra Prasad</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/shailendra-prasad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/shailendra-prasad/</guid><description>Shailendra (Shailey) Prasad, MD MPH is the Carlson Chair of Global Health and the Executive Director of the Center for Global Health and Social Responsibility at the University of Minnesota, Professor and Vice-Chair of Education at the Dept of Family Medicine and Community Health at the University of Minnesota, Adjunct Professor at the School of Public Health, and a Fellow at the Institute on the Environment at the University of Minnesota.</description></item><item><title>Dr Swathi S Balachandra</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/swathi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/swathi/</guid><description>Dr Swathi is a clinician and public health researcher who believes in Health Equity and quality health care for all. With a fellowship in HIV Medicine from Vivekananda Memorial Hospital, Mysore, she has worked with tribal, rural communities, people living with HIV, women in sex work and transgender communities delivering primary health care and understanding issues around access to primary health care. She currently practices at PCMH Restore Health, Bangalore and is an honorary Associate under the Health Equity Cluster, Institute of Public Health, Bangalore.</description></item><item><title>Dr Akshay S Dinesh</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/akshay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/akshay/</guid><description>Akshay S Dinesh is a primary care physician and a deep generalist. Akshay works for health equity in Akshay&amp;rsquo;s own ways which includes building software, writing blog posts, engaging with doctors in rich discussions, and bringing an interdisciplinary approach to medicine through focus on social and other distal determinants of health. Akshay is the editor of AFPI Karnataka newsletter and is a prolific blogger. Akshay is an honorary associate with the Institute of Public Health Bangalore under the Chronic Conditions and Public Policies Cluster.</description></item><item><title>Dr Ramakrishna Prasad</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/ramakrishna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/ramakrishna/</guid><description>Dr. Ramakrishna Prasad is Board Certified in Family Medicine (ABFM, USA) with expertise in Infectious diseases. In addition to residency in Family Medicine, he holds a Master’s in Public Health (Infectious Diseases &amp;amp; Microbiology) and Fellowships in HIV/AIDS, Viral Hepatitis, and Faculty Development in Family Medicine from the University of Pittsburgh. Besides significant faculty and leadership level experience in the US and India, he has worked in Grenada (West Indies), Honduras (Central America), and Mozambique (Southern Africa).</description></item><item><title>Dr R Manjula</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/manjula/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/manjula/</guid><description>She has 20+ years of experience in OBG, Women and Child Care, running National Programmes like Tuberculosis, Malaria, Leprosy, AIDS / HIV, NRHM, Polio Eradication etc. She has finely honed leadership, team building, communication, listening, negotiation, quality patient treatment skills and strong ethical beliefs.</description></item><item><title>Dr Gundappa S Havalakod</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/gundappa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/gundappa/</guid><description>Being from Ramdurg Belgaum, he finished his primary and highschool education in his hometown and college in Alvas Mangalore and graduated with MBBS from Mandya Institute of Medical Sciences in 2019 and has been working as a medical officer at Gumballi since then.
He loves being part of public health practice in terms of providing primary, secondary, and preventive care through field workers. Also to directly involve himself in the community trying to find out the actual causes of diseases and suffering in the community.</description></item><item><title>Dr Bharath Padmashali BS</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/bharath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/bharath/</guid><description>Pursued MBBS from S. Nijalingappa Medical College, Bagalkot and MD Community Medicine from Vijayanagar Institute of Medical Sciences, Ballari. With 6 years of experience he is interested in Communicable and Non Communicable diseases Prevention and how this can be implemented in the private sector. He believes that “listening to patients’ problems patiently will be the 1st step in management at Primary care settings”.</description></item><item><title>Dr Vinayashree BS</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vinayashree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vinayashree/</guid><description>Completed MBBS at JJMMC, Davanagere and has experience working in the Department of Neurology, IHBAS, Delhi previously.
She desires to work for the empowerment of women and children.
She feels that the current fellowship “has been knowledgeable and helping me in day to day practice. New guidelines about treatment and management are usually discussed in the group and we learn new things”.</description></item><item><title>Dr Vivek Kumar</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vivek/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vivek/</guid><description>He has three years of experience and loves working in underserved communities to bring positive health outcomes in the population in which he serves. He desires to decrease disease burden overall year by year and not just treat patient illnesses. He says, “working in primary care is satisfactory and rewarding. It brings fulfilment in life. Patients know you and you also know many of them. Healthcare delivery is best when you know the patient because you tailor treatment according to the patient.</description></item><item><title>Dr Rajeshwari BS</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/rajeshwari/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/rajeshwari/</guid><description>Has over 20+ yrs of experience working in primary care, secondary and tertiary care settings. She has been an example of true leadership during the pandemic since 2020. She was awarded the fellowship in 2021. She loves to work for women and children living in urban slums who often have neglected health. She feels that Primary care is the backbone of community based health care, and that strengthening primary care with available resources and manpower is her goal.</description></item><item><title>Dr Ilhaam Ashraf</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/ilham/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/ilham/</guid><description>Having completed MBBS from Bangalore Medical College, Ilhaam has a keen interest in furthering healthcare access in resource-limited settings, and health system - strengthening for underserved communities. She believes quality, patient-centric and contextual primary care is the backbone of any successful community-based healthcare initiative. Having worked to set up a rural community clinic in the remote tribal village of Ijeirong, Manipur, she is currently in transition to work on an HIV/TB/HCV project in the same State.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/about/</guid><description>We know that high quality primary health care is essential to the well-being of the individual and community. The AFPI-Karuna Trust Primary Care Leadership Fellowship was created in 2019 to improve primary health care in rural and urban areas of India. Our vision is to strengthen the training of primary care physicians to realize their full potential as community leaders in addressing the social determinants of health as well as promotive, preventive, curative, and rehabilitative care.</description></item><item><title>Dr Ashwini</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/ashwini/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/ashwini/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dr Dinesh K</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/dinesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/dinesh/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dr Divya</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/divya/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/divya/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dr Srinidhi</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/srinidhi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/fellow/srinidhi/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>