<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advisors on AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/</link><description>Recent content in Advisors on AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr H Sudarshan</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/h-sudarshan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/h-sudarshan/</guid><description>Dr. Hanumappa Sudarshan is an Indian social worker and tribal rights activist. He is well known for his contributions to the upliftment of the forest dwelling tribes (mainly Soligas) in the Chamarajanagar district of Karnataka. He is also a recipient of the Right Livelihood Award and the Padma Shri. Sudarshan was born in Yemalur on the outskirts of Bangalore. He graduated from Bangalore Medical College and became a medical doctor in the year 1973.</description></item><item><title>Dr BC Rao</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/badakere-rao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/badakere-rao/</guid><description>One of the early DNBs in family medicine, teacher and trainer in family medicine over 40 years who built up the Family physicians association in Bangalore from a handful of members to over a thousand members at present. He ran numerous courses for Family Physicians over the years. He has been an examiner for both DNB and FCGP in the past. He was honored to give the keynote address on the inaugural day of the national conference of family medicine FMPC 2018.</description></item><item><title>Venkat Chekuri</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/venkat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/venkat/</guid><description>Prior to Karuna Trust, Venkat joined Vivekananda Kendra, Kanyakumari as a full time worker. After initial training, he went to Arunachal Pradesh to be part of the Integrated Tribal Development programme. He worked as the Secretary of the project at the time of leaving the organization in the year 1998. He then joined Dr. Sudarshan in Tribal and Rural Development organisations namely Vivekananda Girijana Kalyana Kendra (VGKK) and Karuna Trust. Venkat has worked in different capacities in both organizations and became the Trustee of Karuna Trust in the year 2002.</description></item><item><title>Dr Shailendra Prasad</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/shailendra-prasad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/advisor/shailendra-prasad/</guid><description>Shailendra (Shailey) Prasad, MD MPH is the Carlson Chair of Global Health and the Executive Director of the Center for Global Health and Social Responsibility at the University of Minnesota, Professor and Vice-Chair of Education at the Dept of Family Medicine and Community Health at the University of Minnesota, Adjunct Professor at the School of Public Health, and a Fellow at the Institute on the Environment at the University of Minnesota.</description></item></channel></rss>