<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alumni on AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/</link><description>Recent content in Alumni on AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr R Manjula</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/manjula/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/manjula/</guid><description>She has 20+ years of experience in OBG, Women and Child Care, running National Programmes like Tuberculosis, Malaria, Leprosy, AIDS / HIV, NRHM, Polio Eradication etc. She has finely honed leadership, team building, communication, listening, negotiation, quality patient treatment skills and strong ethical beliefs.</description></item><item><title>Dr Gundappa S Havalakod</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/gundappa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/gundappa/</guid><description>Being from Ramdurg Belgaum, he finished his primary and highschool education in his hometown and college in Alvas Mangalore and graduated with MBBS from Mandya Institute of Medical Sciences in 2019 and has been working as a medical officer at Gumballi since then.
He loves being part of public health practice in terms of providing primary, secondary, and preventive care through field workers. Also to directly involve himself in the community trying to find out the actual causes of diseases and suffering in the community.</description></item><item><title>Dr Bharath Padmashali BS</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/bharath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/bharath/</guid><description>Pursued MBBS from S. Nijalingappa Medical College, Bagalkot and MD Community Medicine from Vijayanagar Institute of Medical Sciences, Ballari. With 6 years of experience he is interested in Communicable and Non Communicable diseases Prevention and how this can be implemented in the private sector. He believes that “listening to patients’ problems patiently will be the 1st step in management at Primary care settings”.</description></item><item><title>Dr Vinayashree BS</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vinayashree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vinayashree/</guid><description>Completed MBBS at JJMMC, Davanagere and has experience working in the Department of Neurology, IHBAS, Delhi previously.
She desires to work for the empowerment of women and children.
She feels that the current fellowship “has been knowledgeable and helping me in day to day practice. New guidelines about treatment and management are usually discussed in the group and we learn new things”.</description></item><item><title>Dr Vivek Kumar</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vivek/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/vivek/</guid><description>He has three years of experience and loves working in underserved communities to bring positive health outcomes in the population in which he serves. He desires to decrease disease burden overall year by year and not just treat patient illnesses. He says, “working in primary care is satisfactory and rewarding. It brings fulfilment in life. Patients know you and you also know many of them. Healthcare delivery is best when you know the patient because you tailor treatment according to the patient.</description></item><item><title>Dr Rajeshwari BS</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/rajeshwari/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/rajeshwari/</guid><description>Has over 20+ yrs of experience working in primary care, secondary and tertiary care settings. She has been an example of true leadership during the pandemic since 2020. She was awarded the fellowship in 2021. She loves to work for women and children living in urban slums who often have neglected health. She feels that Primary care is the backbone of community based health care, and that strengthening primary care with available resources and manpower is her goal.</description></item><item><title>Dr Ilhaam Ashraf</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/ilham/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/alumni/ilham/</guid><description>Having completed MBBS from Bangalore Medical College, Ilhaam has a keen interest in furthering healthcare access in resource-limited settings, and health system - strengthening for underserved communities. She believes quality, patient-centric and contextual primary care is the backbone of any successful community-based healthcare initiative. Having worked to set up a rural community clinic in the remote tribal village of Ijeirong, Manipur, she is currently in transition to work on an HIV/TB/HCV project in the same State.</description></item></channel></rss>