<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Faculties on AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/</link><description>Recent content in Faculties on AFPI-KT PHC Leadership Fellowship</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr Dwijavanthi Kumar</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/dwijavanthi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/dwijavanthi/</guid><description>She is an attending Family Medicine Physician at One Community Health, OB Physician Lead, UC-Davis Volunteer Clinical Faculty, and Program Director of KT-AFPI Primary Care Leadership Fellowship.
Education Bachelors of Science in Biomedical Engineering – University of Iowa, 2008 Dual MD and MPH Program – University of Iowa, Carver College of Medicine, 2015 Family Medicine Residency – Santa Rosa Family Medicine -2018 Dwijavanthi was born in Bangalore, India and immigrated to the US at the age of 7.</description></item><item><title>Dr Eric Wilson</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/eric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/eric/</guid><description>He is an attending Family Medicine Physician, One Community Health, UC Davis Volunteer Clinical Faculty, and KT-AFPI Primary Care Leadership Fellowship Core Faculty.
Education BS in Economics, Math, and French – Iowa State University, 2008 MA in Economics – Duke University, 2010 MD – University of Iowa, 2016 Family Medicine Residency – Santa Rosa Family Medicine – 2019 Primary Care in Psychiatry Fellowship – UC Davis, 2020 Eric was born and raised in Dubuque, Iowa.</description></item><item><title>Dr Swathi S Balachandra</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/swathi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/swathi/</guid><description>Dr Swathi is a clinician and public health researcher who believes in Health Equity and quality health care for all. With a fellowship in HIV Medicine from Vivekananda Memorial Hospital, Mysore, she has worked with tribal, rural communities, people living with HIV, women in sex work and transgender communities delivering primary health care and understanding issues around access to primary health care. She currently practices at PCMH Restore Health, Bangalore and is an honorary Associate under the Health Equity Cluster, Institute of Public Health, Bangalore.</description></item><item><title>Dr Akshay S Dinesh</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/akshay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/akshay/</guid><description>Akshay S Dinesh is a primary care physician and a deep generalist. Akshay works for health equity in Akshay&amp;rsquo;s own ways which includes building software, writing blog posts, engaging with doctors in rich discussions, and bringing an interdisciplinary approach to medicine through focus on social and other distal determinants of health. Akshay is the editor of AFPI Karnataka newsletter and is a prolific blogger. Akshay is an honorary associate with the Institute of Public Health Bangalore under the Chronic Conditions and Public Policies Cluster.</description></item><item><title>Dr Ramakrishna Prasad</title><link>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/ramakrishna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phcleadershipfellowship.afpikarnataka.in/faculty/ramakrishna/</guid><description>Dr. Ramakrishna Prasad is Board Certified in Family Medicine (ABFM, USA) with expertise in Infectious diseases. In addition to residency in Family Medicine, he holds a Master’s in Public Health (Infectious Diseases &amp;amp; Microbiology) and Fellowships in HIV/AIDS, Viral Hepatitis, and Faculty Development in Family Medicine from the University of Pittsburgh. Besides significant faculty and leadership level experience in the US and India, he has worked in Grenada (West Indies), Honduras (Central America), and Mozambique (Southern Africa).</description></item></channel></rss>